JESSLYN LANDGREN

full-stack developer | engineer | geographer

PORTFOLIO: jesslynlandgren.com

jesslyn.landgren@gmail.com

704.779.8391

GITHUB: github.com/jesslynlandgren

I'm a full-stack developer specializing in the MEAN stack and geographic visualization tools. I am a strongly detailoriented person with a love for organization and eager to apply those skills to development. I move easily between both halves of the stack and am looking for employers who make my continued learning a priority.

RECENT PROJECTS

AirNav

Dec 2016

Demo: airnavATL.com

Github: https://github.com/jesslynlandgren/airnavATL

Summary: Group Project #2 @ DigitalCrafts. Web and mobile app that gives turn by turn directions for point to point trips within the ATL airport. Responsible for concept, graph network development,

and front-end

Skills Used: JavaScript (AngularJS), Leaflet, Python, HTML

TripGoalie

Oct 2016 - MARTA Hackathon

Demo: tripgoalie.com

Github: https://github.com/SoccerStreets/soccerstreets

Summary: Web app to facilitate safe travel of minors on MARTA. Worked with one other team member to developed the database and back-end user account functionality.

Skills Used: Python/Flask PostgreSQL, Bootstrap

Nerd Review

Oct 2016

Demo: nerdreview.co

Github: https://github.com/jesslynlandgren/nerdreview

Summary: Group Project #1 @ DigitalCrafts. Developed a site for expert and niche product reviews. Served as Scrum master for the group, and coded both on the front-end and back-end. Responsible for grid sorting feature and README.

Skills Used: Python, Flask, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS

Memory Monsters

Nov 2016

Demo: http://jesslyn-memory-game.surge.sh

Github: https://github.com/jesslynlandgren/memory_game

Summary: Game to simulate classic memory card game. User flips one card at a time and tries to match a pairs.

Skills Used: JavaScript, AngularJS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

EDUCATION SKILLS

Sep 2016 - Present Immersive Development Coding Bootcamp Python/Flask Digital Crafts (Atlanta, GA) HTML **CSS** Aug 2014 - Present M.A. Geography, Geoinformatics cert. **JavaScript (MEAN Stack)** University of Iowa (Iowa City, IA) Java **PostGresSQL** Aug 2012 - May 2014 Non-degree studies (Bio & Ag Eng.) **Tableau** North Carolina State University (Online) Leaflet / Mapbox AWS/EC2

Aug 2006 - May 2010 **B.S. Environmental Engineering**

Georgia Institute of Technology (Atlanta, GA)

LINKEDIN: linkedin.com/in/jesslynlandgren BLOG: http://medium.com/@jesslyn.landgren

WORK EXPERIENCE

Aug 2014 - Aug 2016 Graduate Fellow, IGERT GEEMaP Trainee

University of Iowa (Iowa City, IA)

Geoinformatics for Environmental and Energy Modeling and Prediction (GEEMaP). Performed interdisciplinary group and individual graduate level research while completing additional training in science communication & research ethics. Projects included: spatial analysis of election-related tweets and python tools for processing the twitter stream

June 2011 - July 2014 Associate Engineer II

Environmental Consulting & Technology, Inc. (Iowa City, IA)

Primary engineer responsible for maintaining asset information and environmental reporting for two electric transmission systems, including: SPCC plans, environmental audit results, site layout plans, PCB equipment listing, and Tier II reporting

May 2009 - Aug 2009 Junior Engineering Intern

SCANA (Cayce, SC) - Corporate Environmental Services

Provided general departmental support across multiple projects including: field and desktop wetland delineation, EMS implementation evaluation (ISO 14000), emissions calculations, web documentation of local environmental regulations for inter-company reference.

May 2008 - Aug 2008 Undergraduate Researcher

UNC Charlotte (Charlotte, NC) - Department of Civil & Environmental Engineering

Developed and implemented field data collection system to evaluate and study success of SolarBee mixing technology in Lake Don T. Howell

SERVICE

2011 - Present Midwest Region Chair - Semifinal Interviews

Georgia Tech Stamps President's Scholarship Program

Fall 2015 - Spring 2016 Grad Student Rep

Graduate Program Committee, Geography Department (University of Iowa)

Fall 2015 - Spring 2016 Grad Student Committee Member

President's Council on Teaching (University of Iowa)

Fall 2015 - Spring 2016 Grad Student Committee Member

Family Issues Charter Committee (University of Iowa)

HONORS

Aug 2014 - Aug 2016 Graduate Fellow

National Science Foundation, IGERT Trainee Fellowship

Aug 2006 - May 2010 President's Scholar

Georgia Institute of Technology